《蜘蛛侠3》
我是彼得·帕克 你所熟知的友善邻居
It's me, Peter Parker. Your friendly neighborhood... ...you know.
自从被蜘蛛咬了之后 我经历了太多的事情
I've come a long way from being the boy who was bit by a spider.
对我来说一切好像都不太正常了 但现在...
Back then, nothing seemed to go right for me. Now...
哦 看 是蜘蛛侠
Wow, look, it's Spider-Man!
- 实在太酷了 - 蜘蛛侠
- Super cool! - Spider-man!
大家确实都很喜欢我
...people really like me.
等一下啊 过一会儿还要重播的
Stick around. It's gonna start again in a couple minutes.
行了
That's okay.
城市安然无恙
The city is safe and sound.
我猜这也有我的一份功劳
I guess I've had something to do with that.
我的叔叔班也一定会以我为荣的
My Uncle Ben would be proud.
我还是会去上学 成绩也不错
I still get to school. Top of my class.
汉密尔顿函数告诉我们的就是
Now, the Hamiltonian shows us...
能级是由能量场所决定的
...that the energy levels are perturbed by the electric field.
从这个矩阵的形式 我们能看到什么呢?
From the form of this matrix, we can see?
斯塔西小姐?
Miss Stacy?
那就是说只有质量为零的量子态才会受其影响
That only the "m equals zero quantum states" are affected.
正确 说的不错 斯塔西小姐
Correct. Good work, Miss Stacy.
帕克? 你还有什么要补充的吗?
Parker? You got something to add?
没有了 先生
No, sir.
我与我的梦中女孩坠入了情网
And I'm in love with the girl of my dreams.
嗨
Hi.
华森小姐给我留了一张票 彼得·帕克
Miss Watson left a ticket for me. Peter Parker.
不好意思 抱歉
Excuse me. Sorry.
多谢 抱歉
Thank you. Sorry.
我好紧张啊
I'm so nervous.
那是我的女朋友
That's my girlfriend.
- 我觉得她很棒 - 是啊
- I thought she was good. - Yeah.
哈利?
Harry?
哈利!
Harry!
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我想要解释一下
Explain things.
那就跟我父亲说吧 那会让他起死回生的
Tell it to my father. Raise him from the dead.
我是你的朋友 哈利 我也很在乎你的父亲
I'm your friend, Harry. I cared about your father.
亲爱的!
M. J!
- 彼得! - 祝贺你!
- Peter! - Congrats!
- 我还行吗? - 行吗? 你简直太棒了
- Was I good? - Good? You were great.
- 你真的是... - 你说了 太棒了
- You were... - You said great.
我喜欢这些花 它们真漂亮 是哈利送的
I love my flowers, they're beautiful. And those are from Harry.
- 他今晚来了吗? - 来了 我在外面碰到他了
- Was he here tonight? - Yeah, I ran into him outside.
- 那你们怎么样了? - 一言难尽啊
- What's with you guys anyway? - It's complicated.
再跟我说一遍 我是不是很棒?
Tell me again. Was I really good?
我好紧张啊 膝盖一直在发抖
I was so nervous. My knees were shaking.
- 你的膝盖很好 - 但是欢呼声好像不太热烈啊
- Your knees were fine. - The applause wasn't very loud.
是吗 挺好的啊! 嗯 这是个声学问题!
Yes, it was. Well, it's the acoustics.
与其传播的方式有关 声音会以波群的形式传播
It's all about diffusion. It keeps the sound waves from grouping.
当声音形成波动时 会向前传播 就像是...
When the sound waves, they propagate, then it's like an...
你这个书呆子!
You are such a nerd.
你看到了吗?
Did you see that one?
你知道吗?
You know what?
我下半辈子都想这样在舞台上演唱
I'd like to sing on-stage for the rest of my life...
你要坐在第一排
...with you in the first row.
我一定会去的
I'll be there.
告诉我 你爱我
Tell me you love me.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱死你了
I love you so much.
一直如此!
I always have.
- 准备好了? - 是的
- Ready? - Yep.
你不能躲在这儿 弗林特!
You can't hide here, Flint.
- 我只是来看我女儿的 - 你是个逃犯
- I'm just here to see my daughter. - You are an escaped convict.
警察正在找你 你不能接近她
The cops are looking for you. You're not getting near her.
你只不过是个普通的小偷而已
You're nothing but a common thief.
- 你可能还杀了人 对吗? - 不是那样的
- You maybe even killed a man? - It wasn't like that.
不是的
It wasn't.
我那么做都是事出有因的
I had good reason for what I was doing.
事实就是这样
And that's the truth.
你还是和你的事实一起呆在监狱里 享受你们的一日三餐好了
You and the truth, sitting in prison, having three meals a day together.
我也在所谓的事实中生活着呢
I live in the presence of great truth...
这个事实就在你身后的那间卧室里面呢
...and that is the truth that you left behind... ...right there in that bedroom.
佩妮
Penny.
我很想你
I missed you.
我也想你 爸爸
I miss you too, Daddy.
我保证 我一定会让你的身体好起来的
I promise I'll make you healthy again.
不管如何 我一定会弄到钱的
Whatever it takes, I'll get the money.
你给我出去 马上!
You get out of here. Now.
我不是坏人
I'm not a bad person.
只不过运气比较坏罢了
Just had bad luck.
彼得 这是怎么了?
Peter, what is it?
是关于玛莉的事
It's M.J.
- 我想向她求婚 - 哦 彼得
- I'm gonna ask her to marry me. - Oh, Peter.
你的叔叔班向我求婚的时候 我们都怕得要命
The day your Uncle Ben asked me to marry him, we were so scared.
很激动
And excited.
当然也很年轻
And very young.
我是如此的爱他
And I loved him so fiercely.
- 然后你就答应他了? - 没有
- And you said yes, right? - No.
我想答应他 但是我没有
I wanted to say yes, but I said no.
我还没有准备好 他也没有
I wasn't ready. Neither was he.
因此我们继续等待
So we took our time.
一起期盼着那一天的到来
Looked forward to it.
人们不能仅仅只靠爱情生活下去
Didn't want to run into something with nothing to count on but love.
一个男人一定要明白这一点
A man has to be understanding...
然后才能向女孩子求婚
...and put his wife before himself.
你能做到吗 彼得?
Can you do that, Peter?
是的 我想我可以
Yeah, I think I can.
那我祝你成功
Then you have my blessing.
我希望你最好考虑一个计划
I hope you've considered a proper proposal.
你的叔叔可是周密安排过的
Your uncle had it all planned.
他在一个周日把我带到海边
He took me to the beach one Sunday.
他穿着泳衣是如此的迷人
Oh, he was a knockout in his bathing suit.
我看起来也不差啊
And I didn't look too bad myself.
我们都是游泳健将
We were very good swimmers.
那天天气不错 然后他说：
And it was a beautiful day and he said:
"咱们游到那个岛上去吧"
"Let's swim to the island."
在那个岛上 我们在一棵老树边找到个不错的地方
And at the island, we found a perfect spot by an old tree...
躺在那里 仰望着天空
...and we lay down and looked up at the sky.
然后她说 "闭上眼睛 梅! "
And then he said, "Close your eyes, May."
然后我闭上了 他又说 "可以睁开了"
And I did. And then he said, "Open them."
我又睁开了眼
And I did.
看到他正拿着这只戒指
And he was holding this ring.
光芒四射的...
Dazzling...
就在我的眼前
...in front of me.
我觉得就像太阳一样
I thought it was the sun.
到八月份
We'd be married 50 years...
我们就结婚50年了
...come August if...
因此...
So...
我希望你能为玛莉好好准备一番
...I hope you'll make it very special for Mary Jane.
做些让她永生难忘的事情
Do something she'll never forget.
把这个给她
Give her this.
快点 拿着
Go on. Take it.
- 哈利 - 你知道是怎么回事的 彼得
- Harry. - You knew this was coming, Pete.
你听我说 我没有杀死你的父亲
Listen to me. I didn't kill your father.
他想杀了我 但是却误杀了自己
He was trying to kill me. He killed himself.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
我还在这儿呢 彼得
I'm still here, Peter.
烦死那些玩意儿了
Hate those things.
哈利?
Harry?
哈利
Harry.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
哈利!
Harry!
快点!
Come on!
天啊
God.
- 心脏除颤仪 - 电压200
- Defib. - Two hundred.
好了
And clear.
没有反应
No response.
- 重新充电 再试一次 - 好了
- Recharge, let's go again. - Go ahead.
- 充电 - 好了
- Charging. - And clear.
无反应
No response.
重新再试一次 好了
Let's recharge and do it one more time. And clear.
斯塔西队长
Captain Stacy.
- 怎么了? - 弗林特·马克
- What's this? - Flint Marko.
我们确信是班·帕克凶杀的嫌犯
The guy we tied to the Ben Parker homicide.
- 他怎么了? - 从莱克岛的监狱逃跑了
- What about him? - Broke out of Rikers.
- 现在呢? - 仍然在逃
- And? - He's on the run.
他在沼泽地现身了 我们发现他了
He's in the marshlands. I think we got him.
就在那儿
There he is.
你们两个从西面包抄 汤米 走东边
You two, take the west side. Tommy, take the east.
跑哪儿去了?
Where did he go?
- 电容充电完毕 - 好的
- Capacitors charged. - Right.
唐尼 在一号机出现了小的波动
Donnie, we got a little fluctuation on one.
- 硅元素的质量有改变 - 可能是只鸟 等会儿就飞走了
- There's a change in the silicon mass. - It's probably a bird. It'll fly away.
开始进行分子合成
Initiating demolecularization.
- 他怎么样了? - 会好起来的
- How is he? - He's gonna be okay.
但可能会出现记忆缺失的现象
But there's been some memory impairment.
特别是他的短期记忆
Particularly his short-term memory.
他现在不记得那场事故了
Right now he can't remember the accident...
还有最近身边发生的所有事情
...or anything that happened to him recently.
会一直这样吗?
Is it permanent?
可能吧 只有时间才能证明
It could be. Only time will tell.
他醒了 你可以去看他了
He's awake if you wanna see him.
我还是等一下吧
Maybe I should wait.
没关系的 简单说一下就行了 他还需要休息
No, it's fine. Just keep it brief. I want him to rest.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
嘿
Hey.
撞到头了
Hit my head.
是啊
Yeah.
医生说我遇到意外了
Doctor said I was in an accident.
撞了我就跑了
Hit-and-run.
我都记不起来了
I don't remember much of anything.
我爸爸...
My father...
他死了 对吗?
...he died, right?
这简直是太不可思议了
This is all so weird.
嗨 我尽快赶过来了
Hi. I got here as fast as I could.
这张脸我认识
I know that face.
你怎么样了?
How you doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
我记得的最后一件事 就是我很好
Last thing I remember, I was fine.
在某处
Somewhere.
你现在也很好
You're still fine.
我们都很爱你 哈利
We love you, Harry.
感觉就像是...
It feels like...
出去了很长很长的一段时间
...somehow I've been gone for a really long time.
现在我又回家了
And now I'm back home.
看到你能回来太好了
It's good to have you back.
抱歉 我想可能得让你们离开了 好吗?
I'm sorry, I'm gonna have to ask you guys to scoot, okay?
- 好的 - 那好 多谢
- Okay. - All right. Thank you.
好吧 我们明天见
Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
好的 太棒了
Yeah. Great.
睡会儿吧
Get some sleep.
- 我想他会好起来的 - 我想也是
- I think he's gonna be fine. - I think so.
- 你们看起来也不错啊 - 是啊
- And you guys seem great. - Yeah.
你的朋友都很可爱
You have lovely friends.
我的最好的朋友
My best friends.
我甚至愿意把生命交给他们
I'd give my life for them.
- 怎么了? - 是我
- Yeah? - It's me.
嗨
Hey.
彼得 我打不开门了
Peter, you know I can't open the door.
又卡住了?
It's stuck again?
过来帮帮我吧
Just come on and help me.
我来了
I'm coming.
- 嘿 - 那些评论
- Hey. - The review.
- 他们不喜欢它 也不喜欢我 - 哦 他们不会讨厌你的
- They hated it. They hated me. - Well, they can't hate you.
"年轻的华森小姐是个漂亮的姑娘...
"The young Miss Watson is a pretty girl...
赏心悦目 声音却不够动听
...easy on the eyes, but not on the ears.
她的声音太小以至于都传不到第二排! "
Her small voice didn't carry past the first row."
这太荒谬了 我就在那儿呢
That's ridiculous, I was right there.
你在第一排呢
You were in the first row.
没错 这个... 听着 你真的很棒
Yeah, this... Listen, you were great.
那是个批评家 你想成功必须要学会适应这个
That's a critic. This is something you're gonna have to get used to.
相信我 我能理解 蜘蛛侠也总是被人攻击
Believe me, I know. Spider-Man gets attacked all the time.
这不是说你 是说我 有关我的职业生涯
This isn't about you. This is about me. It's about my career.
我知道 我想说的是 你不应该被这种东西击倒
I know, and I'm just saying you can't let it bring you down.
你应该相信自己 振作起精神来
You gotta believe in yourself and pull yourself together.
你已经步入正轨 并且...
You get right back on the horse and...
别再跟我扯这些了
Don't give me the horse thing.
真希望你能明白我的感受
Try and understand how I feel.
我只是...
It's just...
我看到这些言论
...I look at these words...
就像是我父亲写的
...and it's like my father wrote them.
所有巡逻车注意 请在第54街和第6街路口处的车辆报告
All cars. All cars in the vicinity of 54th and Sixth Avenue, please report.
一台起重机失去控制 接近时请小心
Crane out of control, approach with caution.
得去搞定他
"Go get them, tiger"?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦 我的天啊 7-A呼叫指挥中心
Oh, my God. 7-Adam to Central.
你派给我们的那个起重机的任务 比我们想象的要大得多啊!
That crane job you sent us on? It's bigger than we thought.
我们需要马上动员所有警力
We're gonna need a major mobilization right away.
把发电机关掉 快点!
Shut it down at the generator. Now!
好的 格温 我有个小秘密 就是我的复印机
Okay, Gwen, I've got a secret: It's my copier.
背景里是什么东西啊?
What is that thing doing in my background?
斯塔西队长
Captain Stacy.
他们简单的说了一下 无法关掉起重机
They got some kind of short. Can't shut down the crane.
给爱迪生打电话 让他切断整个街区的电源供应
Get Edison on the phone. Kill the power to the whole block.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
又回来了
It's coming back.
哦 不
Oh, no.
- 哦 天啊 是格温 - 什么?
- Oh, my God. That's Gwen. - What?
她在那上面干什么呢?
What's she doing up there?
我昨晚见到她了 她说有个模特的活儿
I just saw her last night. She said she had a modeling gig.
- 你是谁啊? - 布洛克 长官 小爱德华·布洛克
- Who are you? - It's Brock, sir. Edward Brock Jr.
我在《号角日报》工作
And I work at the Daily Bugle.
正在跟你的女儿约会
And I'm dating your daughter.
你没事吧?
You okay?
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 蜘蛛侠 等一下 我们报纸需要张照片
Hey, Spidey, hold on. Bugle needs a photo.
- 感谢上帝 你没事 - 爸爸
- Thank God you're okay. - Daddy.
嘿 我是个新人
Hey. I'm the new guy.
新人?
New guy?
你还好吧?
You okay?
从现在起 我要为号角日报专门拍你的照片
From now on, I am gonna be taking shots of you for the Bugle.
那笑一下 你在笑吗? 开玩笑的
So smile. Are you smiling? Just kidding.
- 他们已经有人了 - 谁 帕克吗?
- They got a guy. - Who, Parker?
听着 他挡在在你我之间 就像是个业余爱好者
Yeah, look, just between you and me, guy's kind of an amateur.
你没有注意到那家伙把你拍的有些浮肿吗?
Have you noticed his stuff makes you look a little bloated?
还有... 对了 还有点矮胖
Just... Yeah, a little chunky.
好吧
Okay.
但你不用再担心这个问题了 伙计
But you don't have to worry about that anymore, buddy.
给我点好东西
Dazzle me.
只是些关于广告部门的那些家伙的事情
Just something the boys in the Ad Department and I whipped up.
如你所知 咱们报纸的发行情况已经很棒了
As you know, circulation at the Bugle's been pretty good.
尽管还不如纽约的时代周刊
Though not as good as The New York Times.
还有每日新闻 还有邮报 以及一些其他的小...
Or the Daily News, or the Post, or several other smaller...
快点继续吧 你个废...
Get on with it, you moron...
- 怎么了? - 你的血压 詹姆士先生
- What? - Your blood pressure, Mr. Jameson.
- 你的妻子让我时刻注意你是否发火 - 你去告诉我老婆...
- Your wife told you to watch the anger. - You tell my wife...
十分感谢
Thank you.
因此我想出了些推广计划
So I propose this campaign.
"每日号角" 这个毋庸置疑
"Daily Bugle." That's obvious.
"喝彩 就在现在! " 这个是我提出的
"It's hip, it's now." I came up with that one.
"喔哦! "这个是埃里克森提出的 他简直疯了
"It's wow." That's actually Erickson. He goes crazy.
我们又给出了一堆类似这样的 就像是
We gave him a couple lattes, it's like:
"非常之极! "又是我提出来的
"And how." That's me again.
该吃药了
Time to take your pill.
不是那个
Not that one.
也不是那个
多喝水
Drink plenty of water.
谢谢
Thank you.
接着说
Continue.
- 他很忙 - 我只是要来告诉你 你真的很美
- He's busy. - I'm just here to talk to you, beautiful.
是什么味道?
What's that smell?
不过是伊卡璐罢了 那你呢?
That's a little something called Nice and Easy. What's on you?
我用的是"滚蛋"!
It's called Go Away.
这是我听过的最蠢的创意...
That is the dumbest idea you've ever had...
- 你还真行啊 - 注意血压
- ...and you have had some doozies. - Blood pressure.
嘿 你要去哪儿?
Hey, where are you going?
- 你是谁啊? - 你上周雇的他 一个自由记者
- Who are you? - You hired him last week. Freelance.
- 是吗? 什么味道啊? - 我叫布洛克 先生 小爱德华·布洛克
- I did? What's that smell? - It's Brock, sir. Edward Brock Jr.
我喜欢那件衬衫 这是关于起重机事件的照片
Can I just say I really like that shirt? It's the crane accident.
- 好好瞧瞧吧 - 他喜欢我的衬衫
- Check out the light. - He likes my shirt.
- 嘿 贝蒂 - 嘿 彼得
- Hey, Betty. - Hey, Pete.
你最好马上进去 来了个新人
You better get in there. New guy.
他正要卖他的蜘蛛侠照片呢
He's trying to sell some Spidey photos.
多谢
Thanks.
帕克 你来迟了 可能太迟了 布拉克已经打败你了
Parker. You're late, maybe too late. Bruckner beat you to it.
是布洛克 先生 小爱德华·布洛克
It's Brock, sir. Edward Brock Jr.
- 但是我给你弄到了这个 - 但是他已经给我弄到了这个
- But I got you this. - But he got me this.
我在那儿并没有看到你 你怎么会在那么高的地方?
I didn't see you there. How'd you get that high?
- 爬上去的 差点从旗杆那儿掉下去 - 旗杆?
- Climbed. Nearly fell off a flagpole. - A flagpole?
- 我们用谁的? - 我喜欢伯恩斯坦的
- Which one do we use? - I like Bernstein's.
- 好一点 - 也便宜
- It's better. - Cheaper too.
祝贺你 我们会用你的 我会付你50美元
Congratulations, we'll use yours. I'll pay you 50 bucks.
好的 我现在是你的人了
All right, J.J., I'm your man.
我比那些普通摄影师更懂得 什么样的才是好照片
I know more about a good picture than any photographer.
你瞧 摄影并不仅仅是些 旗杆啊或者其他什么的
See, photography, it's not just about, no offense, flagpoles or whatever.
而是要融合光线 布局 还有戏剧性
It's about lighting. Composition. Drama.
我想要这份工作 先生
I want a staff job, sir.
还有一个女孩 我想要与其厮守终身
I have a girl that I intend to marry...
我猜 我也不知道 我有个愚蠢的小小的梦想
...and I guess, I don't know, I have this stupid little dream...
就是想与这个时代最伟大的报纸主编共事
...of working with one of the greatest newspaper editors of our time.
那就是约拿·詹姆士
J. Jonah Jameson.
哦 我们正好有空缺岗位 约翰逊辞职了 记得吗?
Well, we do have an opening. Johnson quit, remember?
- 你炒了他的鱿鱼 - 不管怎么样吧
- You fired him. - Whatever.
我知道什么样的才是好照片 我也来了很长时间了
I know what makes a good picture and I've been here a long time.
如果有一个工作的话 我想应给给我才对
If there's a staff job, I think I deserve it.
他说得对 约拿 彼得跟我们共事多年了 他干得很不错
He's right, Jonah. Peter's been with us for years. He's done a great job.
你想要这份工作 你也想要
You want a staff job, you want a staff job.
- 那有没有人关心我想要什么呢? - 我啊
- Anybody care about what I want? - I do.
闭嘴 滚出去
Shut up. Get out.
我想要公众知道 蜘蛛侠不过是个微不足道的罪犯
I want the public to see Spider-Man for the two-bit criminal he really is.
他是个冒牌货 混身黏糊糊的 要抓他个正着
He's a fake, he's full of stickum. Catch him in the act.
蜘蛛侠偷饼干
Spider-Man with his hand in a cookie jar.
谁能把这张照片带来 就能得到这份工作
Whoever brings me that photo gets a job.
你们等什么呢 中国的春节吗?
What're you waiting for, Chinese New Year?
我马上开工 老板
I'm on it, boss.
你永远也不会拍到的
You'll never get that shot.
哦 那走着瞧了
Oh, we'll see.
(蜘蛛侠成为城市英雄 蜘蛛侠拯救了警局队长的女儿)
我猜只有一人才能如此与众不同
You know, I guess one person can make a difference.
不多说了
Enough said.
欢迎回家 哈利
Welcome home, Harry.
- 感谢上帝你没事了 - 谢谢你 伯纳德
- Thank God you're all right. - Thanks, Bernard.
- 伯纳德 - 先生
- Bernard. - Sir.
给你个回家的小礼物
Got you a little homecoming present.
- 是你原来的球啊 - 没错
- It's your old ball. - Yeah.
多谢了 伙计
Thanks, buddy.
咱们在后院打得不错 对吗?
We were pretty good in the backyard, weren't we?
咱们都差劲的了 还想加入大学代表队呢
We were terrible. And we tried out for the varsity team.
- 为了那些啦啦队员 - 没错
- For the cheerleaders. - Right.
- 嘿 我有没有女朋友啊? - 我不知道
- Hey, do I have any girlfriends? - I don't know.
你不知道?
You don't?
嘿 伯纳德 我有女朋友吗?
Hey, Bernard. Do I have any girlfriends?
据我所知没有 先生
Not that I know of, sir.
这个地方还不错 嗯?
It's a pretty cool pad, huh?
一般般了
It's okay.
- 最起码我不是为了钱去受伤的 - 当然不是了
- Looks like I'm not hurting for money. - No.
嗯 也许我还可以 让没有女朋友的状况有所改观
Well, maybe I can turn this no-girlfriend thing around.
你知道吗 他一直很感激你 帮我度过高中时候的难关
You know, he always appreciated how you helped me through high school.
要是能多回忆一点关于他的事情就好了
Just wish I could remember more about him.
他是爱你的 这才是最重要的
Well, he loved you. That's the main thing.
嘿 咱们去厨房看比赛吧 去找点吃的
Hey, let's watch a game in the kitchen. Get something to eat.
好的
Okay.
小心
Heads up.
你看到了吗?
Did you see that?
- 还是动作敏捷啊 - 没错
- Still got the moves. - Yeah.
我们为什么要停下来啊?
Why are we stopping?
她在这儿干什么呢?
What is she doing here?
加里会给她的经纪人打电话的
Well, Gary was supposed to call her agent.
嗨 亲爱的 我们一直在联系你呢
Hi, honey. We tried to reach you.
抱歉啊
I'm sorry.
就因为一篇批评?
One critic?
不 是所有的报纸 亲爱的
No, all the papers, dear.
玛莉 亲爱的 坐下说 我跟你解释一下
Mary Jane, honey, sit down. Let us explain it to you.
听着 如果你愿意 我们可以说你病了
Listen, if you'd like, we could say you became ill.
这事儿解决得也太逊了点
That was so poorly handled.
是啊
Yeah.
专心排练吧
Let's just rehearse.
看啊 蜘蛛侠
All right, Spidey.
蜘蛛侠!蜘蛛侠!蜘蛛侠!
Spidey! Spidey! Spidey!
打扰一下 小姐? 能像我再展示一下您的迷人微笑吗?
Excuse me, miss? Could I please see that gorgeous smile?
嗨 埃迪
Hi, Eddie.
简直太美了 绝对该上头版
You're so beautiful. This is front-page stuff.
我还有事要做 等会儿见
I gotta practice. See you later.
- 今晚怎么样? - 今晚不行
- How about tonight? - Not tonight.
为什么不行?
Why not?
不记得那个非常非常激动人心的夜晚了吗?
What about that amazing, amazing night that we had?
我们只不过喝了杯咖啡罢了 埃迪
We had a coffee, Eddie.
嘿 美人儿
Hey, beautiful.
再来一张
One more.
- 你没事吧? - 嗯 我没事
- Everything okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你没有在生我的气了 对吗? - 没有 彼得 我以你为荣
- You're not still mad at me, are you? - No, Peter, I'm proud of you.
嘿 我会从那边旋转着飞进去
Hey, I'm gonna be swinging in from over there.
- 哦 是吗? - 那你知道该在哪里看了?
- Oh, yeah? - So you know where to look.
好好表演一下吧
Give them a good show.
不要担心那些评论
Don't worry about that review.
我们到了明晚就可以将它付之一笑了 我保证
We're gonna be laughing about it tomorrow night, I promise.
好的
Yeah.
那个是不是越狱的人啊?
Isn't that that guy from that prison break?
很像啊
He fits.
嘿 你 站住
Hey, you. Halt.
抄后路
Cover the back.
亲爱的 小心点
Hon, be careful.
他在车里面
He's in the truck.
就在前面
Round the front.
开火
Fire.
纽约的市民们...
People of the city of New York...
我到这儿来是因为我从62楼摔了下来
...I am here today because I fell 62 stories...
但有一个人抓住并救了我
...and someone caught me.
那个人没有要求任何回报
Someone who never asks for anything in return.
他甚至不希望我们知道他是谁
Someone who doesn't even want us to know who he is.
嘿 玛莉
Hey, M.J.
- 哈利 - 嘿
- Harry. - Hey.
彼得呢?
Where's Pete?
- 我猜 可能去给某人照相了 - 是啊
- Taking somebody's picture, I guess. - Right.
真高兴能见到你 你看起来很好 哈利
I'm so happy to see you. You look so good, Harry.
我也从未感觉这么好过
I've never felt better.
连你是谁都不知道了 真是太奇怪了
It's a weird feeling not knowing who you are.
撞了下头 就像小鸟一样无忧无虑了
Bump on the head, I'm as free as a bird.
那你能不能也让我撞一下啊?
Will you bump me on the head?
嘿 彼得说你正在参加戏剧表演
Hey, Pete said you're in a play.
你也来了 还给我送了花
You came. You sent me flowers.
我送花了? 我今晚还会再来的
I did? I'll come again tonight.
你来不了了 因为我被解雇了
You can't. I was let go.
出什么事了?
What happened?
我可能不够优秀吧
I wasn't very good.
哦 是够让人难受的...
You know, this is embarrassing...
但我在高中时还给你写过一出戏呢
...but I once wrote you a play in high school.
- 你给我写了一出戏? - 没错
- You wrote me a play? - Yeah.
哈利 你真是太好了
Harry, that's the sweetest thing.
所以我问你们 当你们没有降落伞 就从天而降时...
So I ask you: When you're dropping without a parachute...
或者是你的店铺被抢 你的房子着了火
...or your store's being robbed or your house is on fire...
谁会将你从坠落的空中救下
...who is it that breaks your fall...
谁会扑灭火焰 拯救你的孩子?
...puts out the flames and saves your children?
蜘蛛侠!
Spider-Man.
他们都爱我
They love me.
那接下来就让我们见识一下...
Then let's hear it for your one and only...
我们的友善邻居 蜘蛛侠!
...friendly neighborhood Spider-Man.
嘿 怎么了? 好样的! 你好吗?
Hey. What's up? All right. How you doing?
厉害啊!
Shazam!
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
蜘蛛侠! 蜘蛛侠!
Spider-Man. Spider-Man.
嘿 在那儿 嘿!
Hey there. Hi.
- 吻他 - 吻他
- Kiss him. - Kiss him.
吻他 吻他 吻他
Kiss him. Kiss him. Kiss him.
来吧 亲一下吧
Go ahead, lay one on me.
- 真的吗? - 是啊 他们会喜欢的
- Really? - Yeah, they'll love it.
- 吻她 - 吻他
- Kiss her. - Kiss him.
不 蜘蛛侠 不
No, Spider-Man, no.
好吧
All right.
希望彼得能够拍到一张照片
Hope Pete's getting a shot of this.
嘿 嘿 你没事吧?
Hey, hey, are you okay?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
嘿 伙计 车顶上是什么啊?
Hey, man, we got something on the roof.
游戏结束了 伙计
Jig's up, pal.
我可不想伤害你 快走吧
I don't wanna hurt you. Leave now.
我猜你可能还没有听说吧 我是这一片的治安官
I guess you haven't heard. I'm the sheriff around these parts.
好吧
Okay.
救命啊!
Help!
这些家伙都是从哪里来的?
Where do all these guys come from?
抱歉 我不会说...
I'm sorry, I don't speak...
但这里是法国餐馆 对吗?
But this is a French restaurant, non?
- 您的名字 先生? - 帕克 彼得
- Name, please? - Parker, Peter.
在这儿呢
Here we are.
两个人的桌子 派克
Table for two. Parker.
- 帕克 - 我就是这么说 派克
- Parker. - That is what I said: Parker.
我有个要求
I have a request.
我的女朋友会来 我有一只戒指
My girlfriend will be coming and I have this ring.
你好
Hello.
哦 那就是说你今晚要求婚了?
Oh, so you want to pop the question tonight, huh?
没错 因此我想有点特别的东西
Yes, and I wanna do something very special.
我喜欢 很浪漫
I love it. Romance.
我是法国人
I am French.
当我示意你的时候 你就把香槟和戒指拿上来
When I signal you, if you'd bring some champagne with the ring...
- 放在她的杯底 - 太棒了
- In the bottom of her glass? - Perfect.
还有 我想在同时...
Also, I thought at the same time...
如果那些演奏家能演奏这首曲子的话...
...if the musicians would play this song...
他们一定会乐意效劳的
Their favorite.
小心别弄丢了戒指
And take good care of the ring.
放心 我用生命担保 先生
Oui, with my life, monsieur.
我喜欢你
I like you.
多谢
Thank you.
好的 那...
Okay, so...
想不想来点香槟?
Oh, would you like some champagne?
怎么会跑到那里面去的?
How'd that get in there?
哦 不要哭
Oh, don't cry.
嗨
Hi.
看看你 哦 太美了
Look at you. Wow, beautiful.
多谢
Thanks.
这地方你能消费的起吗?
This place in your budget?
哦 这是个特殊场合
Oh, well, it's a special occasion.
你是百老汇的人
You're on Broadway.
我今晚可没有感觉到自己是明星啊
I don't feel like much of a star tonight.
哦 你是明星 你已经是明星了
Well, you are a star. And you've earned it.
彼得...
Peter...
你根本就不明白我现在的感受
...you have no idea how I feel right now.
哦 不 我很清楚你的感受
Oh, no, I know exactly how you feel.
听着 我也经历过这些 这些也无时无刻不发生在我的身上
Listen, I have been through this. It happens to me all the time.
我看到窗户上蜘蛛侠的海报
I see Spider-Man posters in the window...
街上跑着的孩子穿着印有我的毛衫
...kids running around with me on their sweaters...
万圣节产品
Big Halloween item.
我也不知道 我猜我已经变成了某种偶像
I don't know, I guess I've become something of an icon.
就像昨天 他们不停地高呼:"蜘蛛侠! 蜘蛛侠!"
Like yesterday, they kept screaming, "Spider-Man, Spider-Man."
我也不知道 我是说 我有时候在想：
I don't know, you know, I mean, I'm thinking to myself:
"我只不过是个小地方来的书呆子 这一切该是属于我的吗? "
"I'm just a nerdy kid from Queens. Do I deserve this?"
嗨 彼得
Hi, Pete.
嗨
Hi.
嗨 我父母和我正好来吃晚饭
Hi, my parents and I were just having dinner here.
- 你好 我叫格温·斯塔西 - 你好
- Hello. I'm Gwen Stacy. - Hi.
这是玛莉·珍·华森
This is Mary Jane Watson.
哦 终于能够见到你了 彼得成天提起你
Oh, it's so nice to finally meet you. Pete talks about you all the time.
格温是我卡诺斯博士课程的试验搭档
Gwen is my lab partner in Dr. Connors' class.
彼得是个天才 没有他我也许就要放弃了
Pete's something of a genius. I'd be completely lost without him.
我突然想起来了...
Which actually reminds me...
彼得 你有没有拍到我跟蜘蛛侠接吻的照片啊?
...Pete, if you've got a picture of my kiss with Spider-Man...
你能带到班上来吗?
...could you bring it to class?
我太喜欢了 可以贴在我的包包上
I'd really love it. For my portfolio.
毕竟有几个人能被蜘蛛侠吻到呢?
After all, who gets kissed by Spider-Man, right?
确实难以想象
I can't imagine.
哦 真的很高兴能见到你
Well, it was lovely to meet you.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
哦 她和我一起上科学课
Oh, she's in my science class.
并不是她的强项
It's not her best subject.
什么?
What?
那你为什么从来没有提起过她?
How come you never mentioned her?
她是你的试验搭档?
She's your lab partner?
你救过她的命?
You saved her life?
她还觉得你是个天才...
She thinks you're a genius...
她还把她漂亮的手指甲随意搭在你的肩上
...and she had her polished fingernails all over you?
你没有注意到吗?
Or didn't you notice?
她让蜘蛛侠成了城市英雄
And she gave Spider-Man the key to the city.
我永远也不会忘记的
I'll never forget that.
她只不过是一个班上的同学罢了
She's just a girl in my class.
那我问问你
Let me ask you something.
当你吻她的时候...
When you kissed her...
到底是谁在吻她?
...who was kissing her?
蜘蛛侠还是彼得?
Spider-Man or Peter?
- 你这是什么意思? - 你很清楚我是什么意思!
- What do you mean? - You know exactly what I mean.
那是我们的吻啊!
That was our kiss.
你为什么要那么做?
Why would you do that?
你应该知道那会让我怎么想的
You must have known how it'd make me feel.
- 你是不是想甩了我? - 甩了你?
- Do you wanna push me away? - Push you away?
我为什么要甩了你啊? 我爱你
Why would I wanna push you away? I love you.
你是我的女朋友 她只不过是我的一个同学
You're my girlfriend. She's a girl in my class, M.J.
我感觉很不好 对不起 我得走了
I don't feel well. I'm sorry, I have to go.
不要 等一...
No, w...
- 你要去哪儿啊? - 求你了 不要跟着我
- Where are you going? - Please, don't follow me.
来了
Here we are.
嘿 我是玛莉 请在哔一声后留言
Hi, it's M.J. Sing your song at the beep.
喂
Hello.
我希望你能拿起电话来 我不知道是怎么回事...
I wish you'd pick up the phone. I don't know what's going on or...
我也不知道你是否收到了我的短信
I don't know if you got the messages or what.
但是...
But...
...我只是想跟你说说话
...I just wanna talk to you.
好吧 给我打电话 再见
Okay, call me. Bye.
- 喂? - 帕克先生?
- Hello? - Mr. Parker?
是我?
Yeah?
我是32区的尼尔·加特勒探长
This is Detective Neil Garrett from the 32nd Precinct.
我是代表斯塔西队长给你打电话的
I'm calling on behalf of Captain Stacy.
他希望你能到警局来一趟
He would like you to come down to the station.
起初 我们觉得这个人 丹尼斯·卡雷丁
Originally, we thought that this man, Dennis Carradine...
是杀害你丈夫的凶手
...was your husband's killer.
我们错了
We were wrong.
怎么回事?
What?
现在看来卡雷丁先生只不过是个帮凶
Turns out Mr. Carradine was only an accomplice.
真正的凶手仍然在逃
The actual killer is still at large.
你这是什么意思?
What are you talking about?
这个人才是杀害你丈夫的凶手
This is the man who killed your husband.
他叫弗林特·马克
His name is Flint Marko.
他是个经常出入监狱的三流骗子
He's a small-time crook who's been in and out of prison.
你们搞错了
You got this wrong.
两天前他逃走了
Two days ago he escaped.
很显然他向狱友承认了自己的罪行...
Evidently, he confessed his guilt to a cellmate...
此外我们也有许多证人可以证实这件事情
...and we have a couple of witnesses who will corroborate the story.
不 等一下 孩子 你不会这么做的
No, wait, son. You don't wanna do this.
不要!
No!
嘿 上车啊 你干什么呢?
Hey, get in! What are you doing?
你能不能把这些照片拿走啊?
Would you put these photos away, please?
很抱歉 帕克太太? 我知道这很难
I'm sorry, Mrs. Parker. I know this isn't easy...
但是 拜托你 还是有点耐心
...but, please, be patient with us.
我们也正在工作 会抓到他的
We're doing our job. We will catch him.
不 你们并没有做好自己的工作
No, you're not doing your job.
我看着我叔叔死去 然后还追错了人
I watched my uncle die, and we chased down the wrong man.
现在你又说这两年你们又找到的嫌犯? 证人呢?
Now you're telling me you had suspicions for two years? Witnesses?
- 为什么不早告诉我们? - 冷静点
- Why weren't we told about this? - Settle down.
我没办法冷静下来
I have no intention of settling down.
这个家伙杀了我叔叔 现在还逍遥法外
This man killed my uncle, and he's still out there!
L-20公园专用道
L-20 Parkway.
附近的警官请报告自己的位置
All officers in the vicinity, please report.
我们发现了一辆废弃的汽车...
We have an abandoned vehicle...
还有路中间的一个老人
...and an elderly man in the middle of the street.
对不起 是瓦尔·贝什路
Sorry, Wabash Avenue.
彼得 我是玛莉
Peter, it's M.J.
我不是为了晚饭的事来的
I'm not here about what happened at dinner.
求你了 开门吧
Just please open up.
梅婶给我打电话了 告诉了我发生的事
Aunt May called me. She told me about what happened.
她很担心你
She's worried about you.
我也很担心你
I'm worried about you.
不用担心 我很好
Don't be. I'm fine.
我可不想让你去做傻事
I don't want you to do something stupid.
就像是去找杀害我叔叔的凶手?
Like try to find my uncle's killer?
还有做让你自己后悔的事情
And do something you'll regret.
就像是那个家伙
Like with that other guy.
他拿枪指着我 我躲开了 他就摔下去了 我都跟你说过了
He had a gun on me. I made a move and he fell. I told you that.
- 我并没有要指责你 - 10-22 在556...
- I'm not accusing you of anything. - 10-22, auto at 556...
- 你能不能把那个先关上? - 正在从第5-6街口向5-7街口移动
- Will you turn that thing off? - Crossing 5-6 to 5-7.
指挥中心 这里是3-9号车 第六大道的呼叫已收到
Yeah, Central, this is Car 3-9 responding to your Sixth Avenue call.
彼得 我来是因为我担心你
Peter, I'm here because I care about you.
我也知道你犯了一个错 让你有负罪感...
And I know that you made a mistake and that you feel guilty...
但我就是为你而来的
...but I wanna be here for you.
好的 我知道 谢谢你
Okay. I get it. Thank you.
但我很好...
But I'm fine. L...
我不需要你的帮助
I don't need your help.
每个人都会需要帮助的 彼得
Everybody needs help sometimes, Peter.
即使是蜘蛛侠
Even Spider-Man.
90 X射线, 98
Ninety X-ray, 98.
2-4号 金, 收到关于麦迪逊道642号的呼叫
Two-four King, respond to 1031 at 642 Madison Ave.
1-3号 托马斯 收到东107街540号的呼叫
One-three Thomas, respond to 1020 at 540 East 107.
公寓内有男性投诉者 可能在一楼
Male complainant inside apartment. May be on first floor.
10-11号 亨利 有一处住宅 73818...
Three Henry 10-11, I have a residence. 73818...
别伤害我 给我一次机会吧!
Don't hurt me. Just give me a chance!
那么我叔叔呢? 你有给他一次机会吗?
What about my uncle? Did you give him a chance?
你有吗?
Did you?
我在哪儿啊?
Where am I?
这是什么?
What is this?
这感觉...
I feel...
这感觉真好
This feels good.
耶!
Yeah!
这是另一种完全不同的感觉
This is something else.
有什么发现没有?
What do you think?
我从来没有见过像这样的东西
I've never seen anything like it.
我是个物理学家 不是生物学家
I'm a physicist, not a biologist...
到了早上我会再研究一下 做些测试
...but let me look at it in the morning. Run some tests.
可以现在就做吗?
Can we do that now?
看起来它喜欢你
It seems to like you.
- 不要让这东西依附到你身上 - 为什么不?
- Don't let any of that get on you. - Why not?
它具有寄生体的特性
It has the characteristics of a symbiote...
这意味着它需要寄生在 宿主身上才能生存
...which needs to bond to a host to survive.
事实上有时这类生物 一旦它们依附在宿主身上
And sometimes these things in nature, when they bind...
想摆脱它们就非常困难
...they can be hard to unbind.
正在发生一起银行劫案 地点在俾斯麦街202号的第一东亚银行
Bank robbery in progress, First Eastern Bank at 202 Bismark.
据报道另一起沙暴就发生在附近
Another sandstorm is reported in the vicinity.
- 所有车辆小心行驶 - 马克
- All cars proceed with caution. - Marko.
老兄 很喜欢这套新衣服吧
Buddy, love the new outfit.
这正是我所需要的独家新闻 比帕克抢先报道
This is exactly what I need to scoop Parker.
摆出你的招牌动作弹射蜘蛛网
Give some of that web action.
再见 笨蛋
See you, chump.
我怎么惹着你啦?
What the hell?
弗林特·马克
Flint Marko.
- 你到底想对我怎样? - 还记得班·帕克吗?
- What do you want from me? - Remember Ben Parker?
那个被你残忍枪杀了的老人?
The old man you shot down in cold blood?
这到底又碍你什么啦?
What does it matter to you, anyway?
所有的一切
Everything!
该是血债血偿的时候了 马克!
It's time to pay, Marko!
安息吧
Good riddance.
- 房租 - 现在没有
- Rent. - Not now.
听着 这是个自由的国家 但不是免房租的国家
Listen, it's a free country. It's not rent-free country.
- 少惹我 - 你得交房租
- Leave me alone. - Give me rent.
你想要房租 那你得先修好这该死的房门!
You'll get your rent when you fix this damn door!
看来火药味很浓
That wasn't cool.
他脾气向来很好
He is a good boy.
肯定是碰到麻烦事了
He must be in some kind of trouble.
弗林特·马克是杀死叔叔班的凶手
Flint Marko, the man who killed Uncle Ben...
他昨晚被杀死了
...he was killed last night.
噢 天
Oh, my.
发生什么事了?
What happened?
蜘蛛侠杀死他了
Spider-Man killed him.
蜘蛛侠?
Spider-Man?
我这就不明白了
I don't understand.
蜘蛛侠不会杀人的
Spider-Man doesn't kill people.
到底发生什么事了?
What happened?
我...
I...
他...
He...
他是...
He was...
我想你会觉得...
I thought that you'd feel...
他罪有应得的 是吧?
He deserved it, didn't he?
我不认为我们有权力去评判
I don't think it's for us to say...
别人是否应该活着或死亡
...whether a person deserves to live or die.
但是他杀死了叔叔班 梅婶
But, Aunt May, he killed Uncle Ben.
班对我们非常重要
Uncle Ben meant the world to us.
但他绝不愿我们有丝毫的
But he wouldn't want us living one second...
复仇心理
...with revenge in our hearts.
这好比毒药
It's like a poison. It can...
它能够控制你
It can take you over.
在你察觉到之前 就把我们变成一些丑陋的东西
Before you know it, turn us into something ugly.
- 他说这主意不错 - 好
- He said it was a good idea. - Yeah.
喂?
Hello?
嘿 哈利 我是玛莉
Hey, Harry, it's M.J.
嗨
Hi.
我想找个人陪陪我
I need some company.
你忙吗? 我可以去看你吗?
Are you doing anything? Can I stop by?
当然 过来吧
Yeah, sure, come on over.
好的 你确定不会打扰你吧?
Okay. Are you sure it's okay?
当然 我现在没事儿 快过来吧
No, I'm not doing anything. Please, come over.
- 好的 待会儿见 - 很好
- Okay, I'll see you soon. - Great.
再见
Bye.
- 伯纳德 - 有何吩咐 奥斯伯恩先生?
- Bernard. - Yes, Mr. Osborn?
有位客人要到访 你能去准备一些吃的吗?
We're having a guest. Can you get some food?
- 一位客人? - 对 一位客人
- A guest? - Yeah, a guest.
- 是"客人"的客人吗? - 别问那么多了 你去准备吃的吧
- A "guest" guest? - Will you just get some food?
马上就去 先生
Right away, sir.
嘿 迪克维奇先生
Hey, Mr. Ditkovitch.
- 吃橙子吗? - 不吃 谢谢
- An orange? - No, thanks.
我对刚才发生的事情感到很抱歉
Listen, I'm really sorry for what happened earlier.
我不该大声抱怨这房门 这没有什么值得生气的
I shouldn't have yelled about that door. It was nothing to be angry about.
没有关系
It's no big deal.
但如果你心里感到不安的话 你可以找个时间请我吃披萨
But if you feel that bad about it, you can buy me pizza sometime.
- 不如就今天吧? - 好啊
- Today's good. - Okay.
- 那电话有什么问题吗? - 没有 我只是...
- Have problem with the phone? - No, no. I was just...
我在琢磨说什么好
Well, I was trying to figure out what to say.
如果你给女人打电话 你就说
If it's a woman you're calling, then you say:
"你是个优秀的女人 我是个优秀的男人"
"You're a good woman. I am good man."
- 嗨 彼得 - 嗨
- Hi, Pete. - Hi.
他在给女人打电话
He's calling a woman.
你在给玛莉打电话吗? 我想这很好...
Mary Jane? I think that would be so good...
关你啥事? 去 去 打电话吧
This is none of your business. Go. Go. Call.
- 你应该打电话给玛莉   - 谢谢
- You should call. - Thanks.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
嗨
Hi.
- 你饿了吗? - 是的
- You hungry? - Yeah.
来吧
Come on.
- 我希望你喜欢辣椒 - 我喜欢
- I hope you like peppers. - I love them.
- 不 - 来吧
- No. - Please.
噢 奶油
Oh, the butter.
干得漂亮
Beautiful.
你仔细看好
Check this out.
我们可以吃这部分
Well, we can use that part.
你一直在梦想
You've been dreaming.
只不过是自欺欺人 好度过那漫漫长夜
Nothing like a little self-deception to get you through the night.
- 好吧 - 你什么时候写的?
- All right. - When did you write that?
- 12年级 - 剧情很紧凑
- Twelfth grade. - It's intense.
- 那么你想演出那部分? - 我非常荣幸参与演出你的戏剧
- So you want the part? - I'd love to be in your play.
那是你的了
It's yours.
你知道吗 甚至连个疤痕都没有
You know, there's not even a scar.
看不出来
Barely.
- 对不起 - 我也对不起
- Sorry. - Me too.
- 我不是故意的 - 不 没关系 请原谅我
- I didn't mean to do that. - No, it's okay. Please, forgive me.
玛莉
Mary Jane.
- 玛莉 - 对不起
- Mary Jane, please. - I'm sorry.
只不过...
Just...
你没有按计划去做
You've taken your eye off the ball.
哈利
Harry.
你都干了些什么?
What have you done?
为我报仇!
Avenge me!
- 我父亲 他死了 是吧? - 对
- My father, he died, right? - Yeah.
只是希望我可以想起更多关于他的事情
Just wish I could remember more about him.
他爱你 那是最重要的事
Well, he loved you. That's the main thing.
我在我父亲坟墓前发誓 蜘蛛侠要偿还这一切
I swear on my father's grave, Spider-Man will pay.
哈利
Harry.
还记得我吗?
Remember me?
是的 爸爸 我记得
Yes, Father. I remember.
我对她和彼得的看法是对的
I was right about her. About Peter.
对所有的事情的看法都是对的
About everything.
你知道你必须做些什么 让他痛苦
You know what you must do. Make him suffer.
让他生不如死
Make him wish he were dead.
首先 我们要攻击他的心
First, we attack his heart.
嗨 是我 在哔一声后留下你的美妙歌声
Hi, it's me. Sing your song at the beep.
嘿 M.J. 我是彼得
Hey, M.J. It's Peter.
我想跟你谈谈昨晚的事情
I wanna talk to you about last night.
我不知道昨晚我在想些什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
我知道你去那儿是想帮我 但我...
I know you were just there to help and I...
我不知道 我想见你
I don't know. I wanna see you.
如果你想彼得活命的话 你得为我做些事情
If you want Peter to live, you're gonna do something for me.
- 谁啊? - 乌苏拉
- Yeah? - It's Ursula.
进来吧
Come in.
- 嗨 彼得 - 嗨
- Hi, Pete. - Hi.
有电话找你
There's a phone call for you.
是玛莉 她给你回电话了
It's Mary Jane, she called back.
- 真的吗? - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 我把电话筒放在那上面 - 谢谢
- I put the phone on top of the thing. - Thanks. Okay.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
噢 我真高兴你给我打电话 我想尽...
Oh, I'm so glad you called. I've been trying to...
- 你能来见我吗? - 当然
- Can you meet me? - You bet.
- 现在? - 行 在哪儿?
- Now? - Okay. Where?
在公园里的桥上
At the bridge in the park.
- 我这儿就来 - 好的
- On my way. - Okay.
嘿 我爱你
Okay. Hey. I love you.
你真美
You look beautiful.
牡丹花
Peonies.
- 你还好吧? - 不好
- You okay? - No.
我得告诉你一些事情 彼得
There's something I have to tell you, Pete.
好吧
Okay.
我和你之间的感情
It's not working.
出现了问题
You and me.
什么?
What?
我不想再见到你了
I don't wanna see you anymore.
你在说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
我不知道
I don't know.
我很寂寞
I'm lonely.
你不能为我解除寂寞
You aren't there for me.
我再也受不了
I can't do this.
- 我们之间的关系完了 - 不 求你不要这么说
- It's over. - No. Please. Please don't say that.
我知道我一向自私 但我可以做得更好 我能改
I know I've been selfish, but I can do better. I can change.
- 事情并不是那么简单 - 我们彼此相爱 我爱你
- It's not that simple. - We love each other. I love you.
我们是有问题 当人们碰到问题时
We have problems. When people have problems...
他们会想办法解决 他们跟对方交谈
...they work it out. They talk to each other.
听着 你明白吗?
Look, you see?
你知道这是什么吗?
You know what this is?
- 你知道我对我们的期望吗? - 我有别人了
- You know what I want for us? - There's someone else.
我爱上另外一个人了
I've fallen in love with someone else.
干得漂亮
Bravo.
她说她感到寂寞 我不能为她解除寂寞
She says that she's lonely, that I'm not there for her.
有了第三者
There's another guy.
那么你准备如何承受这一切?
Well, how you holding up?
不是很好
Not good.
哈利 我打算向她求婚的
Harry, I was gonna propose to her.
真的吗?
Really?
她最近一段日子比较困难 关于她的事业
Well, she's been going through a tough time lately. Career.
我的意思是 在爵士俱乐部当歌手女招待
I mean, a singing waitress at a jazz club?
不是她心目中想要的工作
It's not exactly what she had in mind for herself.
歌手女招待? 你在说些什么?
Singing waitress? What are you... What are you talking about?
呃 她被剧组解雇了 她没有告诉你吗?
Well, she was fired from the show. Didn't she tell you?
她被解雇了?
She was fired?
她被解雇了 她告诉了你? 却没有告诉我?
She was fired and she told you? She didn't tell me?
对 这也是我要你到这来的原因 彼得
Well, that's why I asked you here, Pete.
我是那个第三者
I'm the other guy.
什么?
What?
有个下午她遇到麻烦来找我
Look, she came to me one afternoon, troubled.
她需要人陪 我那时在她身边
She needed someone and I was there for her.
我一直都爱着她 彼得 这是你知道的
I've always loved her, Pete. You know that.
这刚刚...
It just...
开始
...started.
我不相信这是真的 我不...我不相信你
I don't believe this. I don't... I don't believe you.
我感到非常抱歉
Look, I'm really sorry.
我只是觉得你应该知道
I just thought you should know.
- 需要添点热咖啡吗? - 好的 谢谢
- Can I warm you up? - Yes, please.
这果馅派怎么样?
How's the pie?
很好吃
So good.
你想喝点东西吗?
Would you like a drink?
对不起 我在想什么呢?
I'm sorry. What was I thinking?
有损公众形象 对吧 城市英雄先生
Bad for the public image, right, Mr. Key-to-the-City?
你对她干了些什么?
What did you do to her?
我做那些你没有做到的事情 我在她身边 替她解除寂寞
I did what you failed to do. I was there for her.
玛莉和我 我们互相了解
Mary Jane and I, we understand each other.
- 她不知道你的真面目 - 彼得 她非常了解我
- She doesn't know what you are. - Peter, she knows me very well.
当她吻我的时候 正如她过去吻我一样
And when she kissed me, it was just like she used to kiss me.
那味道...
That taste...
好像草莓
Strawberries.
感觉如何 蜘蛛大侠?
How'd you like that, Spidey?
就这些了吗?
That all you got?
- 感觉刺痛 对吧? - 我在高中时保护你
- Stings, doesn't it? - I protected you in high school.
现在我要教训教训你这兔崽子
Now I'm gonna kick your little ass.
你要像杀死我父亲那样杀死我吗?
Gonna kill me like you killed my father?
我不会再去试着让你相信什么了 （不是我杀死你父亲）
I'm done trying to convince you.
你把他从我这儿夺走了 他爱我
You took him from me. He loved me.
不 他看不起你
No. He despised you.
你让他脸上无光
You were an embarrassment to him.
看看这个小妖怪 想哭吧?
Look at little Goblin Junior. Gonna cry?
蜘蛛侠过去总是让我充满安全感
Spider-Man used to make me feel safe.
现在我害怕下班后走路回家
Now I'm afraid to walk home from work.
- 我儿子脑海里全是这家伙 - 我有个女儿 爱死了蜘蛛侠
- My son thought the world of this guy. - I have a daughter, loves Spider-Man.
- 她该崇拜谁? - 这就是他们推崇的那个城市英雄吗?
- Who's she to look up to? - This is the guy they gave the key to?
我要抹黑你
I'm gonna put some dirt in your eye.
- 为新摄影师同事干杯 - 嘿 我只是比较幸运
- Cheers to the new staff photographer. - Hey, I just got lucky.
你真了不起
This is so wonderful for you.
你或许告诉詹姆士去弄大点的墙壁空间
Well, you might wanna tell J.J. To make a little more wall space.
早上好 今天天气真好 是吧?
Wow, good morning. It's a beautiful day, huh?
你是怎么说的来着? 我永远不会拍到那相片?
What was it you said? I'll never get that picture?
你的偶像在那儿
There's your hero.
- 我从没有想过他真是那样的 - 看到了没有? 就在那儿
- I never thought he'd really do that. - See? Right there.
你有依据吗? 你得相信你所看到的
You made a judgment call. You gotta see it as it is.
你这么说真有趣
Funny you should say that...
因为我浏览了一些旧相片 看到这相片
...because I was looking through some old photos and it looks very...
很眼熟
...similar.
好了 呃 我得回去干活了
Okay. Well, I gotta get back to work.
- 你好没出息 布洛克 - 什么?
- You're trash, Brock. - Excuse me?
你的相片是伪造的
Your picture's a fake.
噢 帕克 你不要太小孩子气了
Oh, Parker, you are such a boy scout.
你什么时候才会原谅别人呢?
When are you gonna give a guy a break?
你想要谅解? 去信教吧
You want forgiveness? Get religion.
- 这里出什么事了? - 你们没事吧?
- What's going on here? - Are you guys all right?
对 没事 我们只是在闹着玩的
Yeah. No, we... We're just horsing around.
好了 我求你了 如果你这样做 我会失去所有的一切
Look, I'm begging you. If you do this, I will lose everything.
城里不会再有报馆会聘请我
There's not a paper in town that will hire me.
你早就应该想到这点
You should've thought of that earlier.
你在干什么 彼得?
What are you doing, Peter?
把这个给你的编辑看看 告诉他记得下次检查照片来源
Show this to your editor. Tell him to check his source next time.
这是假的
It's a fake.
纽约摄影协会证实了
Empire State Photographic Department confirms it.
卷包袱给我滚蛋
Pack your things. Get out of my building.
- 我只是... - 你被炒了
- I was just trying... - You're fired.
现在我们得刊登撤回相片的声明了
We're gonna have to print a retraction now.
我没有刊登撤销声明20年了
I haven't printed a retraction in 20 years.
- 喂 - 帕克先生 我是卡诺斯博士
- Hello. - Mr. Parker, Dr. Connors here.
噢 卡诺斯博士 你好吗?
Oh, Dr. Connors. How are you?
你上次留给我的实验品相当古怪 帕克
Quite a specimen you left me, Parker.
它的化学组成不像七十年代的球粒陨石
Its chemistry is not unlike the chondritic meteorites of the '70s.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 很好吃 - 你知道吗 帕克?
- That's good. - You know what, Parker?
- 帕克? - 去拿杯牛奶给我
- Parker? - Get me some milk.
它放大宿主的特性
It amplifies characteristics of its host.
- 嘿 再给我一块曲奇饼 - 特别是攻击性方面
- Hey, give me another cookie. - Especially aggression.
这会很危险
This could be dangerous.
彼得 你没有保留一部分 是吧?
Peter, you didn't keep any, did you?
- 你有没有带果仁的牛奶? - 我有果仁 我可以做一些
- You got any with nuts? - I have some nuts. I could make some.
- 那去做一些给我 - 彼得?
- Go make me some. - Peter?
没有 没有 当然没有
No, no, no. Course not.
这些相片真是太好了
These shots are so good.
我很愿意给你拍照
I'd love to shoot you sometime.
彼得·帕克 彼得
Peter Parker. Peter.
帕克 布莱恩特小姐 我雇你们可不是干那个的
Parker. Miss Brant, that's not the position I hired you for.
穿黑衣服的蜘蛛侠
Black-suit Spider-Man.
彼得 这些真是不可思议
Peter, these are incredible.
- 我们需要这些照片 约拿 - 我按老价钱给你
- We gotta have these, Jonah. - I'll pay you the usual rate.
如果你想要这些照片 你得正式聘用我
If you want the shots, I'll take the staff job...
价格加倍
...double the money.
佩妮
Penny.
你真的该来这儿的酒吧玩玩
You are really gonna dig this joint.
你觉得我怎样? 穿着合适吗?
Do you think I'm... I'm dressed all right?
太鲜艳还是...?
Too fancy or too...
你在说笑吧? 你看上去很好 宝贝儿
Are you kidding me? You're looking fine, babe.
- 谢谢 - 我喜欢你的笑声
- Thank you. - Love that little giggle.
嘿 伙计 就让那开着好了
Hey, keep it open there, pops.
噢 真是酷毙了
Oh, this is so cool.
我还从没有到过爵士酒吧呢
I have never been to a jazz club before.
噢 希望我们能找到一张桌子
Oh, I hope we can get a table.
帮我们找一处光线比较暗的
Find us some shade.
谢谢 美腿小姐
Thanks, hot legs.
这边来 先生
Right this way, sir.
噢 谢谢
Oh, why, thank you.
- 我真是太喜欢这地方了 - 我也是
- I am so loving this. - Oh, me too.
- 那不是你以前的女朋友吗? - 是的
- Isn't that your old girlfriend? - Yeah.
- 你想换别的地方吗? - 噢 不 不 我没事
- Do you wanna go someplace else? - Oh, no, no. I'll... I'll be okay.
玛莉 露两手给大家看看
Mary Jane, show us what you got.
- 我很快回来 - 好的
- I'll be right back. - All right.
彼得?
Peter?
这是献给你的
This is for you.
双倍票价的表演来了
Double-time.
谢谢
Thanks.
现在该到这个了
Now dig on this.
太辣了
That is hot.
你所做的这些全是为了她?
That was all for her?
对不起
I'm so sorry.
- 你还好吗 玛莉? - 我没事
- You all right, Mary Jane? - I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
你发什么疯啊?
What's wrong with you?
你
You.
- 有什么可以为您效劳的吗? - 没有
- Can I help you, sir? - No.
这里一切都好吧 保罗?
Is everything okay here, Paul?
对 这里一切都好吧 保罗?
Yeah, is everything okay here, Paul?
- 把他领出去 - 我们走吧 先生
- Take him out of here. - Let's go, sir.
- 把你的手拿开 - 马上走
- Take your hand off of me. - Now.
- 好吧 - 嘿 放手
- Okay. - Hey, get off. Let go.
住手 彼得
Peter, stop it!
你是谁啊?
Who are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是布洛克 先生
It's Brock, sir.
小爱德华·布洛克
Edward Brock Jr.
我今天来到你面前
I come before you today...
满怀谦卑
...humbled...
和屈辱
...and humiliated...
来请求您一件事
...to ask you for one thing.
我想请您杀死彼得· 帕克
I want you to kill Peter Parker.
帕克
Parker.
- 嗨 彼得 - 嗨
- Hi, Peter. - Hi.
看起来你并没有怎样改变过你的房间
You don't seem to have changed the room around very much.
当然 也没有什么可以让你改变的 是吧?
Of course, there's not much you could do, is there?
当我们通电话的时候
When we spoke on the phone...
我感觉到你有心事
...I sensed that something was bothering you...
所以我决定过来看看
...so I thought I'd just come by.
玛莉还好吗?
How's Mary Jane?
我不知道
I don't know.
我没有听到过你的消息
I never heard from you.
你向她求婚了没有?
Did you ever propose?
你说过
You said...
当丈夫的需要为妻子着想
...a husband's gotta put a wife before himself.
我还没有准备好
I'm not ready.
但是发生了什么事?
But what happened?
你如此肯定?
You seemed so sure.
对
Yeah.
我...
I...
我伤害了她 梅婶
I hurt her, Aunt May.
我不知道该怎样做才好
I don't know what to do.
那就从最困难的部分做起
Well, you start by doing the hardest thing:
你不要自责
You forgive yourself.
我信任你 彼得
I believe in you, Peter.
你是个好人
You're a good person.
我相信你会找到办法把事情解决好
And I know you will find a way to put it right.
并且及时的解决好
In time.
蜘蛛侠 受死吧
End of the line, Spider-Man.
我也想他死 弗林特
I want him dead too, Flint.
这就是我找你的原因
That's why I've been looking for you.
噢 对了 我知道你的所有事情
Oh, yeah. I know all about you.
好像是蜘蛛侠不让你帮助你那可怜的女儿
Like the fact that Spider-Man won't let you help your poor daughter.
在我看来 这太可恶了
It's just... That doesn't seem right to me.
我想杀死这蜘蛛 你也想杀死这蜘蛛
Look, I wanna kill the spider, you wanna kill the spider.
我们联手 他必死无疑了
Together, he doesn't stand a chance.
感兴趣吗?
Interested?
没错
Yeah.
那么...
So...
去哪儿?
...where to?
全纽约人都屏住呼吸
All New York is holding its breath...
关注人质事件进展
...as the hostage crisis continues to unfold.
大约30分钟前
Just 30 minutes ago...
警察来到这惊人的现场
...police came across this startling sight:
一个被劫持在的士当人质的年轻妇女
A young woman, held hostage in a taxi...
悬停在离地面80层楼高的地方
...suspended 80 stories above the ground...
那里就像一张巨大的蜘蛛网
...in what appears to be a giant web.
警方所有试图搭救人质的行动
Every attempt by the police to rescue the hostage...
都被那沙人阻止
...has been thwarted by the Sandman.
参与其中的
Compounding the danger...
还有一名奇怪的黑衣人
...is the appearance of a strange black-suited figure.
早期报道相信他是穿黑衣的蜘蛛侠
Early reports had believed him to be the black-suited Spider-Man...
但现在他被证实是完全不同的个体
...but he has now been identified as something entirely different.
人质被确认是玛莉·珍·华森
The hostage has been identified as Mary Jane Watson...
一个最近在百老汇很少登台的女演员
...an actress recently seen in a brief stint on Broadway.
我们现在带你到现场去看看
We're now going to take you live to the scene...
詹妮弗·杜根就在现场 詹妮弗?
...with Jennifer Dugan. Jennifer?
我们大约在100英尺外
We're only about 100 feet away now, Hal, and...
等等 蛛网上好像有动静
Wait. There seems to be some kind of activity in the web.
他们好像在写一些巨大的字母
They seem to be creating some kind of gigantic lettering.
蜘蛛侠面临着一场正面的挑战
Spider-Man's being challenged to some sort of confrontation.
我们不得不面对一个严峻问题
And that raises serious questions...
就是面对如此势不可挡的挑战 他取胜的机会有多大
...about what kind of chance he'd stand against such overwhelming...
哈利?
Harry?
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
我不能打赢他们俩 不能单靠我一人
I can't take them both, not by myself.
你不配我的帮助
You don't deserve my help.
哈利
Harry...
她需要我们
...she needs us.
出去
Get out.
如果我可以的话 先生
If I may, sir?
我看见这屋里发生过的很多事情 但我从未说过
I've seen things in this house I've never spoken of.
你想告诉我什么?
What are you trying to tell me?
你父亲死的那晚
The night your father died...
我清理他的伤口
...I cleaned his wound.
穿透他身体的刀刃
The blade that pierced his body...
来自他的滑翔机
...came from his glider.
我知道你试图捍卫你父亲的荣誉
I know you're trying to defend your father's honor...
但毫无疑问 他是死在自己的手里
...but there's no question that he died by his own hand.
我爱你的父亲
I loved your father...
就像我爱你一样 哈利
...as I have loved you, Harry.
也和你的朋友爱你一样
As your friends love you.
瞧
Look.
蜘蛛侠! 蜘蛛侠! 蜘蛛侠!
Spider-Man! Spider-Man! Spider-Man!
正当所有的希望就要全落空的时候
He seems to have come out of nowhere...
他好像凌空跳出来
...to answer the prayers of the city...
回应城里的祈祷者
...just when all hope seemed to be lost.
彼得 他们要把我们两个都杀死
Peter. They're gonna kill us both.
- 我要把你从这里救出去 - 小心
- I'm gonna get you out of this. - Watch out.
嘿 帕克
Hey, Parker.
天哪 埃迪
My God. Eddie.
我的蜘蛛感觉在隐隐作痛
My spider-sense is tingling...
如果你知道我在说什么
...if you know what I'm talking about.
我们能找到解决问题的办法
We can find a way to settle this.
你说的太对了
You're so right.
我在考虑用羞辱的方法
I'm thinking humiliation.
就像你羞辱我的那样
Kind of like how you humiliated me.
你没有忘记吧?
Do you remember?
你还记得你是怎样对付我的吗?
Do you remember what you did to me?
你让我失去了我的女朋友 现在我也要让你失去你的女朋友
You made me lose my girl. Now I'm gonna make you lose yours.
怎么样 大侠?
How's that sound, tiger?
坚持住 玛莉!
Hold on, Mary Jane!
玛莉!
Mary Jane!
这一切简直难以令人相信
It's hard to believe what's happening.
实在是太残忍了
The brutality of it.
我不知道他能否继续承受下去
I don't know how he can take any more.
对于纽约人民来说 这是个令人悲伤的日子
This could be a tragic day for the people of New York.
这可能是蜘蛛侠生命结束的一天
It could be the end of Spider-Man.
- 了不起 - 真酷
- Awesome. - Wicked cool.
你来了
You came.
好像时间刚刚好 及时赶到
Looks like just in the nick of time.
几分钟之前 事情也不是很糟
A couple minutes ago wouldn't have been so bad either.
我们要怎么做?
What are you gonna do?
我这里可能需要帮助
I may need some help over here.
我现在正有点忙
I'm a little busy right now.
把你的手递给我
Give me your hand.
帕克! 帕克 在哪儿呢?
Parker! Parker, where?
我需要一个摄影师
I need a photographer.
嘿 小孩 你需要一份工作吗?
Hey, kid, you want a job?
我为什么需要一份工作? 我还是小孩子
Why would I want a job? I'm just a kid.
- 好吧 你的相机多少钱卖? - 一百块
- All right, how much for the camera? - One hundred bucks.
一百块?
A hundred bucks?
好吧 你这小奸商 给你
All right, you little crook. Here.
他妈...
What the...
胶卷另计
Film's extra.
打中了
Gotcha.
彼得 正上面
Pete, up top.
玛莉
Mary Jane.
- 事情还能更糟吗? - 抓住
- This thing got any more? - Hang on.
抓住什么?
To what?
- 去吧 老兄 - 抓住她
- Go, buddy. - Got her.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
- 那就好 - 嘿 彼得
- Good. - Hey, Pete.
我没有打扰你们吧?
Am I interrupting?
千万不要伤害
Never wound...
那些你不能够杀死的...
...what you can't kill.
埃迪 你得脱掉那套衣服
Eddie, the suit, you gotta take it off.
噢 你喜欢这套衣服 是吧?
Oh, you'd like that, wouldn't you?
我知道穿着那套衣服的感觉
I know what it feels like.
非常好
It feels good.
那力量 所有的一切
The power. Everything.
但你会失去自我
But you'll lose yourself.
脱掉它吧
Let it go.
我喜欢做坏人
I like being bad.
这让我感到高兴
It makes me happy.
哈利!
Harry!
彼得 你要干什么?
Peter. What are you doing?
不要!
No!
埃迪!
Eddie!
- 哈利 - 玛莉
- Harry. - Mary Jane.
- 我去找人帮忙 - 不用了
- I'm gonna get help. - No.
留下来吧
Stay.
我不想这样
I didn't want this.
但我没有选择余地
But I had no choice.
我们总要做选择的
We always have a choice.
当你杀死我叔叔时 你总要做一个选择
You had a choice when you killed my uncle.
我女儿快要死了
My daughter was dying.
我急需用钱
I needed money.
我很害怕
I was scared.
我告诉你叔叔 我只要他的车子
I told your uncle all I wanted was the car.
- 怎么啦? - 我需要你的车子
- What is it? - I need your car.
他对我说
He said to me:
"为什么你不放下枪回家去? "
"Why don't you just put down the gun and go home?"
我现在意识到他在试图帮助我
I realize now he was just trying to help me.
然后我看到我的同伴拿着现金跑来
Then I saw my partner running over with the cash.
他手里拿着枪
And the gun was in my hand.
上车
Get in.
做了一件对你非常可怕的事情
Did a terrible thing to you...
我花了无数个夜晚祈祷 希望可以挽回一切
...and I spent a lot of nights wishing I could take it back.
我不是在请求你原谅我
I'm not asking you to forgive me.
我只是想让你了解真相
I just want you to understand.
我也做过可怕的事情
I've done terrible things too.
不是我选择要变成这样的
I didn't choose to be this.
现在唯一令我留恋的
The only thing left of me now...
就是我的女儿
...is my daughter.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
嘿 兄弟 感觉怎样?
Hey, pal. How you doing?
好点了
Been better.
我们会帮你渡过这一关的
We'll get you through this.
不用了
No.
我本不该伤害你的
I should never have hurt you...
说那些事情
...said those things.
所有的事情都不重要了 彼得
None of that matters, Peter.
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
最好的朋友
Best friend.
哈利
Harry.
无论什么挡在我们面前
Whatever comes our way...
无论我们内心斗争多激烈 我们总要做出选择
...whatever battle we have raging inside us, we always have a choice.
我的朋友哈利教会了我这一点
My friend Harry taught me that.
他选择做我最好的朋友
He chose to be the best of himself.
是选择决定了我们成为什么样的人
It's the choices that make us who we are...
我们总是能选择去做正确的事情
...and we can always choose to do what's right.